Nikhileshkumar Ikhar

Product development engineer with 7+ years of experience with M.Tech. in IT. Successfully developed & deployed, platform & behaviour design strategies in well-established corporations as well as emerging startups.

Bengaluru, Karnataka - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Nikhileshkumar-Ikhar/

cb907948c3299ef4

Willing to relocate to: Hyderabad, Telangana - Mumbai, Maharashtra

WORK EXPERIENCE

Product Development

Aggrigator - Bengaluru, Karnataka -

2015 to Present

Aggrigator is Stanford incubated startup. It is an agriculture-based online marketplace in US B2B $_{\rm market}.$

First non-co-founding engineer to come on board reported directly to CTO. Developed Reverse Auction Engine. A farmer would bid for their SKU and engine would pick

farmer based on bidding and capacity.

Developed Palletization engine. A pallet can have multiple SKU boxes from multiple buyers. The

engine generates a packing sequence of boxes in pallets in a truck container according to the $\,$

delivery route.

Developed prototype to categorize SKU with Deep learning.

Owned delivery of functionalities development, behavioural nudges, shaping of platform business

model, aligning of product development to business.

Architected, designed & deployed websites, database, ${\tt UI/UX}$ to facilitate farm fresh produce

procurement & delivery to end consumers. Owned and developed various features like,

Inventory management plays a big role in optimizing cold storage, warehouse and trucking

requirement. It helped in reducing crop wastage.

Invoicing of sold crops and tracking payments.

Order tracking for buyer and seller.

Fetching USDA price list daily via a web crawler.

Generating various reports in online, CSV and PDF format.

Worked with technologies like Python, Django, Celery, MySQL, MongoDB, Ubuntu, Neural

Network.

First, six months employer was Above Solutions.

Software Engineer

Cisco - Bengaluru, Karnataka -

2012 to 2015

Owned and developed several products to help network migration, upgradation, tracking bugs,

tracking

https://www.indeed.com/r/Nikhileshkumar-Ikhar/cb907948c3299ef4?isid=rex-download&ikw=download-top&co=IN

 $\label{lem:https://www.indeed.com/r/Nikhileshkumar-Ikhar/cb907948c3299ef4?isid=rex-download&ikw=download-top&co=IN$

vulnerabilities.

- Presented several proofs of concept for new business requirement.
- \bullet Worked on various technologies such as Python, Java, Django, Celery, Cisco routers, SDN, OnePk & Hadoop.

Worked on network migration during intern

Cisco -

January 2012 to June 2012

System Engineer

Infosys - Pune, Maharashtra -

2008 to 2010

Worked as an SAP Basis consultant. Organised various in house events.

EDUCATION

M.Tech. in IT in VIT, Pune

IIIT - Bengaluru, Karnataka

2010 to 2012

SKILLS

Django (6 years), Java (3 years), MongoDB (3 years), MySQL (3 years), Python (6 years)

LINKS

http://github.com/nik-hil

http://linkedin.com/in/nikhar

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Skills

Python, Django, Celery, Java, AngularJS, HTML, Bootstrap 3, Shell Script, MySQL, MongoDB, Ubuntu

obuiltu

Business Skills

Platform business model, Behaviour design

http://github.com/nik-hil

http://linkedin.com/in/nikhar